# 这就是快速的鸡汤
This is the 'instant' chicken broth
# 简易的 快捷的
Simple, fast
# 而且味道非常鲜美
And very delicious
# 水开了 也得搅起来 关键点
The water is boiling. We need to stir here! This is a key point
# 国宴鸡豆花 这菜还真有难度
State Banquet - Ji Douhua (Chicken tofu pudding). This dish is difficult indeed
# 作为您来讲是不难啊
It's not difficult for you
# 大爷这个还真难
Da Ye, this one is indeed difficult
# 鸡牙子 这里面有个筋膜我给它登出去
'Ji Ya Zi'. Let me remove the fascia here
# 鸡胸里边最嫩的一块肉
The most tender cut in the chicken breast
# 就那么两块 一个鸡
You can only find two pieces of this in one chicken
# 这道菜是川菜里边一个代表菜
This is a representative dish in Sichuan cuisines
# 从豆花演变而来
It evolved from tofu pudding
# 形容它特别嫩 跟豆花似的
Because it is extremely tender, just like tofu pudding
# 它所谓的难渡过去没有机器
The difficult part is... there was no machine in the past
# 过去就得这样砸
So we needed to pound it like this
# 它剁的那筋就进去了
If you chop it, the fascia will be mixed into the meat
# 你看它砸 砸着砸着这膜
Look. As I pound it, the fascia...
# 你看它能砸出来 是不是大爷您看
See? It comes out. Right, Da Ye?
# 别砸了 有机器咱使机器吧
Don't pound it for now. We have the machine
# 过去用刀背砸
We used to pound the meat with the back of the cleaver
# 所以砸的需要一个时间
So it needs to be hit for a certain period
# 砸的越细越好 一个小时
The finer, the better. One hour of pounding
# 所以它有一定的难度 使机器吧
So it is difficult to make this dish
# 这个菜要比例不好 出来就非常老了
The dish will not be tender at all if you use the wrong ratio
# 一斤鸡牙子 水是四百克
For 500 grams of 'Ji Ya Zi', you'll need 400 grams of water
# 加的是葱姜酒水
We are adding the mixture of green onion, ginger, cooking wine, and water
# 要分几步 因为这机器小
You need to separate this step into several times because this machine is small
# 倒出来 这好
Pour it out. Good
# 这样就行
This is ok
# 五克盐
5 grams of salt
# 一百五十克蛋清 跟淀粉和在一块
150 grams of egg white, mixed with starch
# 鹰粟粉 鹰粟粉九十克
'Ying Su Fen' (corn starch). 90 grams
# 鹰粟粉也是淀粉的一种
It is also one type of starch
# 比较白比较细腻
It's white and smooth
# 鸡蛋清跟鹰粟粉和匀了
Mix the egg white with the corn starch
# 跟鸡豆花和好了
And the chicken paste
# 60目箩
60-mesh filter
# 60目的箩过一下 别剌手啊师父
Filter it with a 60-mesh filter. Be careful with your hand, master
# 过箩就使鸡蓉更加细腻
The filtering step makes the chicken paste more smooth
# 出来这个口感滑嫩
The texture will be silky and tender when cooked
# 你要是粗箩
If you are using a filter with larger mesh size
# 它出来以后有渣子 显得糙一点
There will be sediments remaining after filtering
# 所以这个箩的目数一定要比较精准
Hence you must be careful with the mesh size
# 细的就是60目 再粗一点就是40目
Fine mesh size means 60-mesh. A cruder one would be 40-mesh
# 过箩的时候要摁着 手放平
Press it when filtering. Place your hands horizontally
# 你看就下去了
See? It's going down
# 您看还不费劲 全下去了
It's not very hard. All going down
# 您这地道啊大爷
That's authentic, Da Ye
# 冲箩不能用热水冲
Don't wash the filter with hot water
# 好了 我现在可以吊（汤）了
Okay. Now I can prepare the broth
# 鸡胸肉鸡里脊都行
Chicken breast or chicken tenderloin
# 弄一个这汤料的扫子
Let's make a 'Sao Zi' (chopped chicken) for the broth
# 看着啊二伯有高招
Look. Er Bai has a great trick
# 我们在家里头
When cooking at home
# 如果来不及熬鸡汤
If you don't have enough time to prepare the broth
# 你说熬个鸡汤熬好几个小时
For example, you may think it is hard
# 有点困难
to spend several hours on cooking the chicken broth
# 我可以用点鸡胸肉 鸡里脊肉
You can use some chicken breast, or chicken tenderloin
# 直接剁 砸这个就不用很细了
Chop it directly. You don't need to chop it as careful as in the previous step
# 就是拿刀背砸一砸 成一种网状
Just pound it with the back of the cleaver. Make it look like a 'net'
# 到时候我们坐一锅开水
Then you can boil a pot of water
# 把砸好的粗的鸡蓉 下锅一扫
And simply put the crude chopped chicken into the pot
# 这汤就特别鲜了
The soup will be very delicious
# 这是临时吊汤的一种
This is a fast and simple way
# 快捷巧妙的方法
to prepare instant chicken broth
# 好 给点葱姜 来了
Ok. Add some ginger and green onion. Here you go
# 少搁点酒
A little cooking wine
# 然后搁点白胡椒粉 好了
Then some white pepper powder. Done
# 搁点盐 一勺 好了
Some salt. One spoon. Okay
# 看着啊 先把这（开）水 给它转起来
Look. Firstly, swirl the boiling water
# 转起来 倒一半
Swirl it. Add a half (of chopped chicken)
# 转 转
Swirl, swirl
# 看着啊这汤
Look at the broth
# 如果是我们熬的鸡汤 它是浑的
If we are preparing the chicken broth by long-time boiling, it's gonna be turbid
# 它会把鸡汤里边那些杂质
(The chopped chicken) will absorb the
# 通过它的旋转收缩
scums and impurities in the broth
# 就吸收到这鸡蓉身上
by swirling and shrinking
# 尤其我们很多网友
Especially when you need to cook in a short time
# 有时候临时来个任务 吊汤来不及啊
and you may not be able to prepare the chicken stock instantly
# 这一下我们用这种方法
Now we use this method
# 告诉我们网友
and tell you guys
# 简易的快捷的 而且味道非常鲜美
how to prepare instant, delicious chicken broth
# 简易鸡汤快速家庭版
in a short time when cooking at home
# 然后这鸡蓉在加热和成熟的瞬间
The chopped chicken will float onto the surface
# 它会浮起来
when it's heated and cooked
# 我们把肉里边出现的这些沫子
Now we need to completely
# 要把它打干净
remove the scums
# 然后再进行扫第二遍
Now let's clean the broth again
# 你看有时候真没有汤怎么办
However, if you really do not have chicken broth
# 连鸡蓉都没有
Not even chopped chicken
# 反正我在家做饭
Well, when I am cooking at home
# 有时候哪儿有汤啊 就是水
Sometimes I may not have soup, but just water
# 但是煮个面就没味儿啊
but it will taste too bland if cooking noodles with water
# 卧俩鸡蛋 这个汤就鲜美了
In that case, add two eggs. The soup will be much better
# 大家看这汤这水越来越清亮了
See? The soup is becoming more clear and transparent
# 而且还有一点淡淡的绿茶的茶色
Also it comes with a slight green tea color
# 大爷您看这就行了是吧 好第二遍
Da Ye, is this ok? Yeah, let's do the second time
# 这还可以搁三遍的呢
We can do it three times
# 每加一次它这汤就更清一次
Every time you add the chopped chicken into the broth, it becomes clearer
# 小魏赶紧 关小火么 关一点
-Xiao Wei, hurry up! -Lower the heat? -Yes
# 一翻了锅就完蛋
It'll be spoiled if it's boiling
# 好 倒里面
Okay. Pour it in
# 继续转 旋转
Keep it swirling
# 先别理它 先让它收缩沉淀
Leave it alone for now. Let it shrink and condense
# 它就浮起来了
It'll float
# 你看 漂起来了 翻起来了
See? It's floating
# 有时候我们为了汤好看
Sometimes for the appearance of the broth
# 加一些红扫
We use some red meat
# 比如牛肉扫 红的香
For example, chopped beef. Red meat makes the soup more aromatic
# 鸡是鲜
Chicken enhances the umami flavor
# 这时候加盐
Now add salt
# 最着急的是这一瞬间
This is the most nervous moment
# 这个锅是复合底的 上热上的慢
This pot has a complex bottom. The heat goes up slowly
# 而且这还不能大锅滚
You cannot use high heat to boil the broth
# 一滚就翻乱了
The broth will be bad if you boil it violently
# 只要开锅 它不能翻锅
It has to reach the temperature, but not boiling
# 只要一开就得使小火 让它微着开
When it starts to boil, turn to low heat and let it boil slowly
# 你看这一锅吊一小时以后
If you boil one pot of broth for one hour
# 就成半锅了
It'll become half a pot
# 把鸡蓉的味全吊出来了
The flavor of chopped chicken will be driven out completely
# 那时候是最好的了 你知道吗
That's the best cooking time, you know?
# 看啊 要开 关小火了
Look. It's going to boil. Now turn to low heat
# 现在稍微小一点了
Just a little bit less heat
# 还得让它出沫
We still need to wait for all scum to come out
# 有的网友说 什么叫砸一下
Some friends asked, what is 'Za' (literally knock) the broth?
# 这个时候有的这火 调不了那么小
Sometimes you may not be able to use a low-enough heat level
# 这汤开的又挺大
And the broth is boiling violently
# 我们有时候来一点凉水 一砸
You may add some cold water rapidly into the pot
# 等它再一开又有沫子
When it boils again, more scum will come out
# 如果你不砸它一下
If you don't add some cold water
# 这沫子就翻进去了
The scum will go back into the broth
# 哦了 关火
That's ok. Turn off the heat
# 汤一凉的时候 一会它就沉底儿了
The chicken will sink to the bottom when it cools down
# 这时候加味 加盐
Now season it. Add some salt
# 你看 这就特别好看了
Now it looks great
# 这就是快速的鸡汤
This is the instant chicken broth
# 如果燉半个小时
If you boil it for half an hour
# 鸡肉的味道完全吊出来了 特别鲜
The flavor of chicken goes into the broth completely, rendering it with extreme umami flavor
# 所以这个鲜度足够了
The umami flavor is enough now
# 开始做鸡豆花
Let's cook chicken tofu pudding now
# 好第二步啊
Ok. Second step
# 这一杯水啊 混合完了
Now add this cup of water
# 我这慢慢的
Slowly
# 一点一点的让它打进去
Slowly mix it with the slurry chicken paste
# 原来四百克（水）
We added 400 grams of water previously
# 这又加了二百五十克（水）
Now we add 250 grams more
# 六百五十克（水）
In total, 650 grams of water
# 之前不能加
We shouldn't add it in the previous step
# 就跟大爷打这个狮子头似的
Just like when Da Ye cooks 'Shi Zi Tou'
# 一下加足了它就完了
The dish will be a failure if you add water in one go
# 这就是难度
This is the difficult part
# 这差不多吧大爷 这差不多了
-What about this, Da Ye? -It's ok
# 水开了 给它搅起来
The water is boiling. We need to stir it!
# 大火啊关键点
Use high heat. That's a key point!
# 成功
Success
# 是大火啊这会
High heat now
# 我让它开了之后
When it boils
# 稍微一开就赶紧小火十分钟
As soon as it boils, turn to low heat and wait for 10 minutes
# 就别理它了
Now leave it alone
# 看它的变化
See how it changes
# 这让网友学真的这还真有难度
It's really difficult for our audience to practice this dish by themselves
# 没说嘛简单的事情 不简单啊
Well a simple thing may not be as simple as it looks
# 让它不能开了
Don't let it boil
# 就跟煮那汤似的别让它开了
Just like when boiling the broth... Don't let it boil
# 小火不能开啊 不能开锅
Low heat. No boiling!
# 小火似开非开那样
Use low heat and make it somewhere between boiling and not boiling
# 不用搅和
Do we need to stir it?
# 这不能再搅了再搅就散了
No. It'll fall apart if you disturb it
# 你给大爷拿个凳子让大爷坐会
Get a chair for Da Ye and let him sit for a while
# 没事没事我这观察着呢
It's fine. I'm looking at the pot
# 火不到它不抱团
If the temperature is not high enough, the 'tofu pudding' will not aggregate
# 只要全浮起来就ok了
It's done when everything is floating
# 小火慢慢成熟
Let it cook slowly with low heat
# 有八到十分钟就可以了
Leave it for 8 to 10 minutes
# 这让它都得飞出来
We need to remove all the scum
# 就让它似开非开就行了
Let it boil, but not boiling
# 这鸡汤吊着也差不多了
The chicken broth is almost done
# 这也成熟了
This is also done
# 就把这加了热之后
Let's heat the broth
# 就小火别开了就行
Use low heat, don't let it boil
# 温度够就行了
As long as the temperature is high enough
# 这个可以了 这还真差不多了
-This is done. -Yes
# 拿一个漏勺往出盛吧
Get a skimmer to take it out
# 好可以了
Okay. This is ready
# 先盛鸡汤 别攉拢
Get the chicken broth first. Don't disturb it
# 就盛浮头的 攉拢浮起来就下不去了
Take the supernatant. If you disturb it, the scums will never sink again
# 清鸡汤
Clear chicken broth
# 这汤漂亮 香味也往上飘 可以了
This broth looks awesome. Smells great as well. Okay
# 搁这
Put it here
# 跟这边上起 少拢少拢
Raise it from the edge. Take less
# 拿这水（清鸡汤）稍微淋它一下
Rinse it (with the broth) a bit
# 把这上面的浮沫就淋下去了
Such that the scum over it will be removed
# 跟这儿抹进去 抹
Put it in gently. Gently
# 抹进去 别动
Gently. Don't disturb it
# 热的沉不了底
It's hot and it won't sink
# 为什么说要人家要蒸的
Why some people tend to steam it?
# 人家上宴会为什么蒸啊
Why steam this dish in the banquet?
# 就让它浮在面儿上 关火
Steaming will make the tofu pudding float on the surface
# 国宴鸡豆花
State banquet Ji Douhua
# 非常好
Very good
# 少来少来 烫烫
Less please. It's hot
# 国宴鸡豆花
State banquet Ji Douhua
# 汤鲜 豆花鲜嫩 入口没有渣子
Delicious soup. Tender tofu pudding. No scum when eating
# 滑嫩 这个嫩还跟别的嫩不一样
Smooth and tender. The tenderness is somewhat different from the other dishes
# 因为这个菜 当第一次做的时候
This dish... When we cooked it for the first time
# 我们也经过无数次实验 也失败过
We also experienced numerous experiments and failures
# 但是刚才大爷讲的过程
But Da Ye was very specific
# 就非常详细了
about the process
# 而这个汤 要有清汤的良好的功底
For this dish, you need great skills for clearing the broth
# 这豆花 在方的配比上很严谨
Also, the recipe for the tofu pudding is very delicate
# 一次次的我们纠正去改良
We have been correcting and improving this dish continuously
# 二伯 二十年都不干了
Er Bai has been away for his position for 20 years
# 所以说二十多年宝刀未老 老当益壮
but he is still good at it. He becomes better as he gets older
# 在大爷的帮助下
with Da Ye's help of course
# 给二伯一赞 谢谢大爷啊
-Thumb up for Er Bai! -Thanks, Da Ye
# 小魏这汤不热 够热啊师父
-Xiao wei, the soup is not hot enough. -It is, master
# 够热什么啊 这必须得开
No, not at all. It has to be boiling
# 这汤必须得烫嘴
The soup must be very hot for your mouth
# 那宴会就能吃了
That's the standard for the banquet
# 你说 这个烫
Say, the 'hot'
# 八十度跟一百度
at 80 degrees and 100 degrees
# 我跟你说
Let me tell you
# 你呈现出来的东西就差远了
Makes a great difference on your dish
# 大爷你说是不是大爷
Isn't it, Da Ye?
# 为什么要蒸啊
Why steaming?
# 那个啤酒鸭那饺子
Remember the beer duck with dumplings
# 你要汤不热 那饺子是沉底的
If the soup is not hot enough, the dumplings will sink to the bottom
# 这重要的大型的细活啊 小魏
(The banquet is) important and large-scale, but requires great care
# 你还得需要 稍微再磨练磨练
You still need more practice
# 十一点了啊
It's 11 pm now